A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Linda Atkinson FA676
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Linda Atkinson
1973-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Atkinson, Linda
Ford Foundation
FA676
1.31 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1973-1978
Series II. Subject Files, 1973-1979
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Linda Atkinson worked as a program officer at the Ford Foundation for a number of years. She started in the Foundation's Population Program before moving to the Urban Poverty Program following an organizational change in the Foundation's programming.
Atkinson's post-Ford Foundation career included her position as director of clinical development at the AZLA Corporation, a pharmaceutical and medical systems company. She has been involved with the South San Mateo County League of Women Voters since 2018.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Atkinson had a research position at the Population Council. She earned a B.S. in biology from Wheaton College and a Ph.D. in human physiology from the University of Illinois' College of Medicine.
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1973-1978; I
  - Ball, Michael, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Bell, David, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Berelson, Bernard, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Blumstein, Alfred, 1974 September 30 (Box 1)
  - Carmichael, William, 1977 August 22 (Box 1)
  - Chaudhury, Ranjit Roy, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Chedd, Graham -- Chapters for Reproduction Review Policy Report, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Cole, David and Casey, Donn, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Connell, Betty, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Hellman, L. -- Population Research Speech, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Hembree, Wylie, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Jaffe, Fred (Alan Guttmacher Institute), 1973-1977 (Box 1)
  - Koblinsky, Marjorie, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Loupos, John -- Incl. Report Written for Ford Foundation on Biomedical Research Costs, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Luukkainen, Tapani (University of Helsinki), 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Mahoney, Richard, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Patrusky, Ben, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda Re: Reproduction and Fertility Research, 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1977 Chron Files (1/2), 1977 February-June (Box 1)
  - 1977 Chron Files (2/2), 1977 July-December (Box 1)
  - 1978 Chron Files (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1973-1979; II
  - Africa Report -- Ford Foundation/Harvard Review of Research and Support for Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Articles, Reports, and Newsletters Re: Ford Foundation Contraceptive Research and Greep Reports (1/2), 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Articles, Reports, and Newsletters Re: Ford Foundation Contraceptive Research and Greep Reports (2/2), 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Contraceptive Safety and Related Memoranda and Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Grants to Organizations, Fiscal Year End September 30, 1975, 1975 November (Box 1)
  - Letters Re: Donors' Meeting, 1976 (Box 1)
  - "News Briefing for Science Writers - New Developments in Contraception and Fertility Control" -- Conference Program, Papers, Press Release, 1976 December 14 (Box 1)
  - Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development Grant (DAP 739-0813), 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Research Funds and Research Projects in Reproductive Biology, Contraceptive Development and Family Planning -- Grant Lists, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Center for Population Research (CPR) -- Population and Reproductive Biology Report Files -- Inventory Data, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller Foundation -- Population and Reproductive Biology Report Files, 1975-1978 (Box 1)